hop on the internet and you're going to
find dozens of Talking Heads like myself
talking about the many mental and
physical benefits that come with cold
plunging now if y'all know what a cold
plunge is you're basically hopping in
the water that's under 50 degrees for a
Target time around three to five minutes
I've reviewed a handful of cold plunges
by now for y'all and guess what we got
another one today with the Redwood
Outdoors Alaskan cold plunge tub we got
a fun one today so top right on it
[Music]
what's up y'all it's Jake back at the
barbing garage gym and we're outside
today because we got the Redwood
Outdoors Alaskan cold plunge tub in this
video today I'm going to tell you
everything you need to know about this
icy plunge from the price some pros and
cons I noticed and of course who should
or maybe should not buy one of these now
before I do all that I gotta let you
know we've reviewed a ton of coal
plunges on barbin.com so if you want to
browse our best list just go and search
barbin best cold plunges you can find
out for yourself which ones we like the
best
[Music]
all right so let's talk about some
things I like about this cold plunger
first of all we got to talk about the
build so it's made from a Scandinavian
Thermo wood I think that's really cool
there's actually some tree sap right
here on the side and also you know it
just kind of gives it you know that
outdoorsy look hence the name Redwood
outdoors I also like how there's a
built-in seat in here not every single
coal plunge that resembles a barrel like
this you know has that so it just adds
to your comfort you know during those
icy plunges it's also lined with plastic
to help keep it insulated and keep those
water temperatures you know cool and
really where you want it to be and then
lastly you know it's not the most
compact option on the market but once
you compare the size of this to the cold
plungers that resemble a bathtub this is
a really solid option for those who are
tight on space
relax
foreign
now there are a few potential cons on
notice with this plunge so let's talk
about that real quick I want to talk
about money first all right I'm going to
detail everything you know more in just
a second but this lid is not included
with the plunge so the plunge itself is
around two grand which is pretty
expensive you're also going to be using
a lot of water and a lot of ice which
you know you might consider to be
wasteful unless you spend even more
money and go after the chiller that's
going to regulate the temperature for
you speaking of temperature you know
unless you you know go and get that
Chiller it's all going to be you know
impacted by the weather outside so we're
in Nashville middle of summer it's hot
you know I put 60 pounds of ice in here
yesterday and it was all melted within
maybe 15 minutes and that's also you
know because you're using you know hose
water which is only around you know 55
degrees or so and that's obviously
impacted as well you know when it's hot
outside and then lastly I want to talk
about the lack of a hose hookup with
this drain that's going to be a problem
for anybody who wants to direct the
water away from their plunge and you
know anything that's surrounding it so
definitely keep that in mind as well
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some money now
and as always you know products like
this the price is absolutely subject to
change so definitely keep that in mind
but as of right now the Alaskan cold
plunge tub from Redwood Outdoors itself
is right around two grand you know once
you tack on shipping that's around 2 400
bucks that's a chunk of change for you
know a wooden barrel without very many
features going on and guess what it gets
even more expensive so once again this
lid is not included and there's a
floating thermometer if you add those on
it's going to bump it up to around 2130
and then tack on shipping that's over
2500 it's a lot of money now if you want
the chiller to regulate the temperature
for you it's going to bump you up to
around forty eight hundred dollars and
then if you want to take it up a notch
with hot water that's going to be around
fifty eight hundred dollars remember you
still got to tack on shipping so you
could spend over six grand on this
product right here and you know once
again that's a load of cash now compared
to you know the other models out there
it's actually you know pretty average
pricing but that doesn't necessarily
mean that it's cheap now if you want you
can definitely find some cheaper ones
out there or you could just use a
preferably clean plastic trash can and
always hop in that or even your bathtub
at home so keep that in mind as well now
unless you spend you know more money on
that Chiller or the chiller heater combo
this plunge is not going to filter your
water for you so you'll probably want to
scoop up one of those three Water
Maintenance kits they have on their
website so let's talk about them for
just one quick second so the spa Guard
water balancing kit is going to be
focused around decreasing the pH level
and increasing the alkalinity it's going
to run you around 100 bucks or so the
spa guard bromine cleaning kit is going
to cost you around 250 bucks and if you
want to avoid harsh chemicals altogether
you can go after that all natural water
cleaning kit it's going to run you
around 350 bucks so as of now you cannot
purchase the lid separately on their
accessories tab but you can purchase the
floating thermometer for about 30 bucks
and you can also get a new filter
cartridge shirts for about 50 bucks now
when it's all said and done you know
this is an expensive purchase there's no
sugar coating yet but you are paying for
a luxury experience and you're
definitely getting that here you know I
really like the wood I think that's
really sweet you also got the seat built
into it which is really cool you know
not every single cold punch out there
has a designated seat which is you know
obviously a really nice thing and then
you know speaking of the luxury you know
if you go after you know the chiller the
heater you know all that's going to
filter your water for you and that's
about his luxurious as it gets you just
come out here take the lid off and hop
right on into it but you know with a
purchase like this or you're spending
this much money if you're not using it
multiple times a week I think you can
you know make the case that you should
definitely go after a cheaper option
that being said you absolutely can
Finance this purchase so definitely
check that out too
okay so let's talk about the build and
some of the features you'll find with
this cold plunge once again it is made
from Scandinavian thermal wood and
there's even tree sap right here on the
right which doesn't do anything it just
you know speaks to the overall quality
and the fact this is real wood which is
really nice it's just over three feet
tall it's a little over three feet wide
maybe right at three feet wide and the
actual opening itself is right around
two and a half feet wide the seat sits
about a foot or so maybe a little under
a foot from the bottom of the plunge and
then it's about a foot wide so you have
plenty of room for you to sit on it I
really like how it came with this ladder
right here you know it's just easy to
get in and out of it and then you know
obviously you have your drain down at
the bottom remember it does not have a
hose hook up so you know whenever it
comes time to drain the water just be
prepared for you know pooling you know
basically a puddle of water unless you
you know rig something up yourself to
kind of you know direct that water away
it also holds up to 130 gallons of water
which is a lot but you don't even need
that much water in here I would suggest
only doing around 50 to 60 percent of it
or so sorry there's some trucks going on
I guess I don't know that I'm filming
right now but I would only put around 50
you know 60 percent of it with water
that way you can add plenty of ice and
also you know your body you'll be
hopping in it and that water doesn't
overflow everywhere
all right so now it's really time for
the fun here we're gonna do a full walk
around and I'm gonna hop in this cold
Plunge in just a second but I want to
you know just break everything down up
close I really like this uh the steps
right here you know they're really nice
same Scandinavian thermal wood as you
got right here and I really like how
there's a little curve right here so
this C I mean the the steps are just
gonna you know fit nice and snug up
against your plunge which is just a
really cool thing right there now one
thing I forgot to mention earlier and
you could consider this a bit of a con
is that you're gonna have to stain this
wood if you plan on keeping it outside
you know having the sun beat down on it
and everything is actually going to turn
this wood a bit of a grayish color so if
you want to avoid that you know
definitely you know get some stain and
stain this bad boy all right so
we got these I guess clamps you can call
them right here now this came pre-built
so you don't have to worry about dealing
with any of this like I mean whenever
you get the box it's all put together
already which is really nice
um but yeah so that's cool right here
it's Gonna Keep the wood you know nice
and secure and uptight against the
actual tub which is a nice thing now got
your drain down here and this is how it
works it's pretty simple you just twist
it water is going to flow out but
there's no hose hookup right here which
is a bit of a bummer
um you're just gonna have you know a ton
of water just pulled up around your
plunge and that could be a problem
especially you know if you have any
cords electricity you know all that
stuff maybe just you don't want all that
water around you in general so
definitely remember that as well this
lid remember does not come with your
purchase you're definitely going to have
to get this or else all that cold water
is just going to escape and you don't
want that now inside right here I've
already put 60 pounds of ice in here
just a few minutes ago maybe 10 minutes
ago tops and as you can see you know
it's pretty much already all melted as
there's a few pieces right here but it's
pretty much all melted so I'm going to
add some more in just a second but I
just want to go ahead and show you guys
you know you do have your seat right
here you do have your thermometer we're
sitting at 52 degrees right now and I
put 60 pounds of ice in it dropped 30
degrees in about 10 minutes or so so or
25 whatever so that's pretty nice
actually
um you got your seat down there at the
very bottom and you can see your drain
so that's pretty much it honestly guys
now
it's time for the fun part right let me
go ahead and set this lid off to the
side
got my ice right here
that pre-ice bath anxiety is starting to
kick in right now but it's okay
that's how we build no mental customers
all right
all right here we go
let me go all the way under just to
start might as well right
oh
so a bit of a fail on trying to go under
if that's because of that seat honestly
I'm not going to complain about that at
all right now this is really cold I
think we dropped a little bit more right
now we're rocking 50 degrees
it's gonna drop below that which is
ideal it's what you want you know some
of those other ones that have the
chiller and stuff can go below that can
go around 36 degrees might not
necessarily need that it might be a
little too cold actually
um this is definitely going to get the
job done and I actually really like to
see it's deep enough so that pretty much
all my whole body is in it oh
yeah that's pretty cold only problem is
that you know this ice it's already
starting to melt in my body temperature
and also just you know the temperature
outside so definitely keep all that in
mind overall I mean this is pretty solid
you know the inside right here is about
two and a half feet wide so it's really
only a one person plunge three feet wide
in total maybe around five feet with the
the steps right here it's about three
feet tall or so
that's about all there is to it guys
this is a really nice cold plunge and
you know I really like this wood makes
it really high quality
[Music]
all right so let's talk about who should
purchase the Redwood Outdoors Alaskan
cold plunge this is a pretty good space
saving solution for those who are tied
on space that's because it's a little
over you know five feet wide including
the the steps right here but you could
actually stack that on top of the lid
and it's only going to take up about
three feet of space which is a really
nice thing now also I really like how
it's you know plastic that makes it
super easy for you to clean and it's
going to make the inside pretty durable
right here now also really like the wood
you know the little combo right there
makes it really high quality in my
opinion just remember you are gonna want
to you know stain this wood unless
you're keeping it under a carport like
we have right now and then lastly you
know it's just the benefits of cold
plunging in general you know there's a
lot going on you can read and read and
read all about it I'm not going to bore
you to death right now but you know
specifically for me you know dealing
with you know tough situations and you
know putting your body in that fight or
flight you know scenario this is a
really good way to do that and just kind
of you know build more mental toughness
in my opinion which is really cool too
and then when it comes to those who
might not want to purchase this cold
plunge really to me it's just you know
with money and then you know regulating
your water temperature so once again you
know this tub by itself is two grand and
it's not really going to regulate your
temperature you know you can put like I
said I put 100 pounds of ice in here and
this is kind of hanging around a little
bit right now and the temperature is
we're now sitting at 44 degrees it was
at 70 degrees when I put the first 60
pounds in there which is good you know
it dropped but that's you know I just
spent like 50 bucks on ice for one one
sitting so you know that that could be a
bit of a bummer for some people unless
of course you know you go and spend more
money and you go after that Chiller or
the chiller heater combo to where it
just does everything for you but then
you're you know flirting with spending
you know close to six grand on one
product so if you do that you definitely
you want to use it pretty much daily or
maybe even every other day just to make
sure you're really getting your money's
worth but if you don't then you know you
run into that issue of being super
wasteful with you know the plastic bags
the ice comes in the actual ice itself
and all the water and everything so you
know those are really my main reasons on
why somebody would not want to purchase
this bad boy
[Music]
that's all I got for y'all today on the
Redwood Outdoors Alaskan cold plunge
it's one of my personal favorites right
now it's super high quality I really
like those Scandinavian thermal wood
just remember you're going to want to
stain it if it's outside it's pretty
well insulated too with this plastic
which is a nice touch just remember you
know it is an expensive purchase and
you're gonna have to use a lot of water
and a lot of ice you know every time
you're hopping in here unless you spend
even more money and going after the
chiller or the chiller heater that's
going to take care of everything for you
at the end of the day though you're
paying for a luxury experience and you
know you're definitely going to find
that to be evident as soon as you hop in
here I did thanks for watching y'all
hope this video was really helpful I was
able to answer anything you need to know
about this gold plunge as always keep
your eyes posted for my next video but
for now head over to barbin.com because
we have a full written review just
waiting for you to read go ahead and
search barbin Redwood Outdoors Alaskan
cold plunge review our article is going
to pull up you can go over everything we
talked about here today I'll catch y'all
next time
[Music]
foreign